You know, we’ve had a lot of cars
on this show that are old cars,
they’re classic cars,
they’re beautiful,
they’re well kept up,
they’re little works of art.
And then you have those old cars
that people just used as cars.
This is one of those cars.
[Jerry] This is a 1958 Porsche
356 Speedster,
in nonmetallic aquamarine blue
with a black interior.
This is my car.
I use it to go places, to run errands,
take people around, or drive it just
for the sheer unbelievable fun of it.
The Speedster is the most iconic, classic,
timeless early Porsche ever made.
It has a tiny race car windshield,
a slippery aerodynamic shape,
cool little bucket seats,
and a powerful 60 horsepower motor.
What makes this
particular Speedster so special
is that without anyone
taking very good care of it,
it has survived with all its
original parts intact.
Not every car does.
And for 68 years, it’s been running.
-[starts engine]
-And it’s still running.
And I like things like that.
I like things that weren’t
that well taken care of,
but just hung in there
and survived anyway.
[distorted voice over PA]
It really reminds me of
my very special guest today...
Yeah, the cops are coming, Jerry.
[Jerry] Mr. Norm MacDonald.
I don’t want to make a friend,
I just want to find out about this steak.
Norm MacDonald is one of my
favorite comedians.
He is the former host of Weekend Update,
and is now the host of...
Good evening, everybody.
Welcome to Norm MacDonald Live.
[phone ringing]
[Norm] Hello?
[Jerry] Hey Norm, it’s Jerry.
[Norm] Hi, Jerry. Did you bring your car?
[Jerry] I did. Yeah, it’s such a beautiful
day, you’re not going to believe it.
-[Norm] I’m happy.
-[Jerry] How do you feel?
[Norm] This small talk’s helping.
[Jerry] To me, a cup of coffee with
a comedian is my idea of a perfect day.
[Norm] Then this is
the perfect show for you.
[Jerry] Yeah.
[Norm]
Would be like if I had a show called
Eating Count Chocula All By Myself.
[Jerry laughs]
[upbeat music playing]
I’m Jerry Seinfeld, and this is
Comedians in Car Getting Coffee.
-Hey, Norm.
-Hi, Jerry.
Good Christ.
God damn, man. Holy crow.
Oh, God.
-What the [beep]?
-Hey! [cackles]
This is a car?
[Norm] I was hoping you’d bring
a tiny, ancient car.
[Jerry] I didn’t figure on rain.
[Norm] Oh, no.
[Jerry] I’m sorry about that.
A rusty car in the rain.
[Norm] A rusty car in the rain.
[Jerry] That’s the Norm MacDonald story,
isn’t it?
-[Norm] A rusty car in the rain?
-[Jerry] Yeah.
[Norm] Sounds like
one of those sex things.
How much for a rusty car in the rain?
This car is working amazingly well
for the conditions that we’re in,
which really couldn’t be worse.
[Norm] Now you’re changing lanes,
I notice.
Let’s make a list
of incredibly banal observations.
My mother will be in a car
and we’ll be driving, she’ll go,
"Ralphs!" She’ll just
read words on buildings.
[Jerry] Here’s another thing I find
that old people do.
They’re completely surprised when waiters
want to know what you want to eat.
They’re just like, "Oh."
"Oh," and then...
"Oh, okay."
Caught unaware.
"What would you like?"
Always seem to be caught off guard.
One time I went on,
it was like a, a dance floor.
And they gave me a Mr. Mic.
Do you know what a Mr. Mic is?
-Of course.
-So, I’m holding the speaker
and the mic and talking,
and then a guy comes in
from the street, you know...
-Yeah.
-And there’s no sign
advertising for me, right?
So, he thinks I’m a psychotic,
you know, person.
And so he starts approaching me, you know.
Like, you would say,
"Give me the gun," you know.
And I’m like, "No, no,
I’m the performer. I’m the entertainer."
I did a similar gig at a disco in Queens.
And what happened in Queens?
It died a miserable death.
I went to get paid and the owner went,
"I didn’t even know you were on."
I said, "Nobody did."
Are you allowed to swear on this program?
Sure. But I will beep it.
-You know how I am with the words.
-Not gonna use those words.
Well, listen. As I get older,
I understand the value of clean comedy.
Oh, yeah?
And how it’s a superior, now you’re
going to say it’s not superior,
but it is superior.
It’s totally superior.
-You do think it is? Okay.
-Completely.
Would you ever consider
changing your style?
Yes, yes, yes.
I considered for a while because,
you know, I loved Rodney
when he would go on The Tonight Show,
-and just destroy...
-Yeah.
...for eight minutes. Then on the couch,
-destroy for another five minutes.
-Yeah.
And then at the end,
"How’s your week, Johnny?"
-You know, after like just...
-Yeah.
...non-stop knockout punches.
What do you want to do now, huh?
[audience laughing]
That wraps it up, huh?
[Jerry] I’ll go as far as to say this.
I think that cursing ruined his act.
No, I would agree with you.
I had no idea,
as a matter of fact, I was so naive,
I only knew him from
Tonight Show appearances.
Yeah.
And it wasn’t until I got to Los Angeles,
and I was like, "Whoa!"
I think it undermined his charm.
Yeah, even the way he, you know,
he used to dress so beautifully
with the suits.
-Yeah.
-And the character.
And then I go-- Then I went,
what’s the character now?
A guy with bleached blonde hair and
a Hawaiian shirt, you know what I mean?
-It didn’t seem to make any sense.
-Yeah.
[Norm] I was just in, uh,
-Las Vegas, Nevada.
-Yeah.
And I was in the elevator.
So it was just a man and his wife,
and the man says to his wife,
"I don’t care what I told you,
give me the money."
Or the husband yelling at the wife,
"How do you lose $150
in a slot machine?"
And she says, "You lost 15,000."
He says, "Yeah, but I know how to gamble."
[laughs]
The guy who loses, you know, he says,
"My God, I had a terrible day today.
Lost 15 out of 15 in college football,
I lost eight out of eight in baseball,
you know.
I lost six out of six in soccer.
You know, I don’t know
what I’m going to do. You know."
And uh, the other guy goes,
"Well, there’s a hockey game on tonight."
He goes, "I don’t know
anything about hockey."
You like sweaters?
Sweaters? Are you kidding me?
How are you doing financially?
Well, how much money does a fella need?
You know what I mean? You need...
Of course I know what you mean.
It’s a very simple question.
That’s right. Why do I keep saying it?
Now do you think Cosby’s legacy
will be hurt?
-Yeah.
-You do, huh?
I mean, there’s a comedian,
Patton Oswalt, he told me,
"I think the worst part of
the Cosby thing was the hypocrisy."
And I disagreed.
-You disagreed with that?
-Yeah, I thought it was the raping.
Now, it’s my feeling that
most rapists are hypocrites.
You don’t meet many who go,
"I like raping and I know
it’s not politically correct, but by God."
People go, "Well, he’s not being
a hypocrite and that’s the worst part."
Where are we, Jerry?
Man, I could use some hot coffee
-and soup.
-God, I could, too.
I don’t know how my honeycomb
sweater... Look at that sweater, huh?
It reminds me of the Bernie Madoff outfit,
when they accosted him
outside the building.
Think this is similar.
You’re saying that’s a good thing.
Bernie Madoff had a lot of money.
[Norm] Good Christ.
[groaning]
Well, here we are. Isn’t this wonderful?
Look at this, huh?
Everybody slams the door on this car.
You don’t need to slam it.
Here we go, me and Norm MacDonald
-on the worst day of the year.
-Yeah.
-[Norm sighs]
-I’m happy now.
-You are?
-Yeah.
Because you’re inside?
-And I’m with you.
-Yeah, yeah.
And I’m in a diner.
-Aren’t diners beautiful?
-I love them.
-[Jerry] How are you?
-Good afternoon.
-What is your accent?
-[server] Ireland.
-Yeah? Beautiful accent.
-Ireland? Yeah, it’s beautiful.
-Can I get you something to drink?
-Hot coffee please, yeah.
-Yes, I also. Yes, yes.
-[server] Okay.
-Here you are.
-Thank you.
[Norm] Look at that.
These are great cups, by the way.
-This is working out great.
-It is. [chuckles]
-This cup is like perfect for coffee.
-Yeah.
-Man, that’s coffee. It’s good coffee.
-Yeah, that’s really great coffee.
-Great.
-And especially after the wet cold
-that we just came from.
-Whoo.
-And now we’re warm.
-Isn’t this fun?
-Now we’re warm.
-Yeah, well, we’re warm.
Not only by the coffee, but by fellowship.
And the bonhomie.
[snickers]
I almost got you there.
I almost got you to spit up
on "bonhomie."
Is that the goal of comedy?
-Yes.
-Like, I guess, huh?
It’s a good feeling. To make
another comedian spit up a little bit.
-Yeah.
Do you not like the saucer?
-Yeah, no, no.
-Oh.
Man alive.
So what I was going to ask you to do,
the Nixon Watergate.
I have to hear that again.
I would do it because
I love doing Nixon so much.
David Frost is interviewing Richard Nixon.
[Jerry] Right.
Because Watergate was so ridiculous,
Nixon would use that for his own benefit.
So, at one point, David Frost goes,
"Now Mr. Nixon, when E. Howard Hunt
and Gordon Liddy
entered the Watergate Hotel
and broke into the room,
at that moment,
they were carrying listening devices
and, and wigs."
Richard Nixon goes, "Well,
I, uh, I suppose that
they were carrying listening devices,
perhaps you could call them
hearing devices. And wigs."
You like the old shows
that were very high concept?
Did you care for any of those sitcoms?
I liked I Dream of Jeannie
because I love the space program.
-It was Major Nelson and Dr. Bellows.
-I love those...
It was Dr. Bellows
'cause he was the psychiatrist.
Gonna have astronauts,
gotta have a psychiatrist.
-Why?
-Yeah, yeah, it's true. Yeah.
And he could shake it off, you know.
Somebody would appear, disappear.
It would roll right off.
Yeah.
-You remember Kojak?
-Telly Savalas.
-With the lollipop.
Yeah, he had the lollipop going.
So, for the pilot,
it was Crocker’s first day.
You know, Kevin Dobson played Crocker.
Sure. Crocker.
So he was just out of police academy.
-Green.
-Yeah.
They kept saying how green he was.
Kojak had been around a long time,
he knew everything.
So he’s, you know, has this green kid
and he doesn’t know if he even wants
to be working with him.
So, what was happening was,
prostitutes were being murdered,
-you know?
-Oh, my.
He goes, "Go down
and try to get some information
from the prostitute’s mother."
So, a little while later,
Crocker comes back.
"I talked to her mother.
She wasn’t a prostitute at all.
She was a good, good girl."
You know? So, Kojak's seen it all, right?
So, he takes his lollipop, he goes,
"Yep. She was a good girl.
Mama’s apple pie.
The Fourth of July. She was a hooker!"
[laughing]
Crocker was too green to see it, you know?
So that’s a funny one
that anyone can do at home.
This hot sauce is so hot.
Do you like really hot things?
I do, but that is unbelievably hot.
Okay, I'm gonna try this.
-Do you like hot sauce?
-Oh, I hate it.
But you know, you gotta try
new things in life.
-No you don’t.
-Yeah, you’re right.
I don’t know if you had this
when you were young,
but we’d always go, you know,
"We’ll do heroin... when we’re 80!"
-The idea being that once you hit 80...
-Yeah.
-You know, what do you got to lose?
-Right.
Might as well do heroin.
But now that I grow older, I realize,
it’s not like you become fearless
when you become older. It’s the opposite.
You know, I remember my grandmother,
I walked into the room once
and she had a bruise
that went from her wrist
all the way up to her shoulder.
-Big, purple, yellow-ish bruise.
-Wow!
And I said, "My God, Grandma.
Where did you get that?" "The wind."
So, she’s not doing heroin.
When I first started
I used to do a joke about,
when I was a kid my parents
were always telling me
how milk was a nickel,
a car was a quarter,
and I thought, how could the world
change that much again?
Will I be saying to my kids,
you know, when I was a boy,
no dogs could vote.
They were just pets.
I remember that joke.
-You do?
-Yeah, yeah, yeah.
-No dogs could vote. That's awesome.
-Wow.
You don't have a child.
-Pardon me?
-You don't have a child.
-So, you don't have to worry about...
-I don't?
I have three.
You have three daughters?
I have a daughter and two sons.
What?
I guess we can agree to disagree,
but I thought you had no children.
-Well, that's what you thought, then.
-Whoa!
Son of a gun, that’s hotter
than a two-dollar pistol.
Man alive.
How do you feel about John Hinckley
walking the streets of DC?
And yet attempted murder and murder
-are the same thing. Yeah.
-Same thing.
Well, it’s a different skill level.
What about manslaughter?
Less than murder, but sounds way worse.
The other one is if you kill
more than one person,
that’s called "special circumstances."
Which sounds to me
like a custom-made jacket.
Now, you can buy one off the rack,
but we also have these
special circumstances.
-A bespoke jacket.
-Yeah.
It just sounds like a very elegant term
for murdering lots of people.
Well, let’s just call it...
special circumstances.
One of the most hellish things
was that Richard Speck, you know...
-Yeah.
-...busted in and killed,
and raped-- killed all the nurses.
But I remember he was charged with,
whatever, nine counts of rape,
nine counts of murder,
and one count of breaking and entering.
Not only did you enter,
you broke something.
-Yeah, I never thought of that.
-Yeah.
That doorknob is broken.
-Who’s going to pay for that?
-You’re right.
When I first came to Hollywood,
I wrote for Roseanne, you know.
And I remember looking
at the first script, you know,
because when you come in
from a standup perspective,
and you read these jokes,
you go, "Every joke’s gonna bomb."
Like, you know,
and I remember telling people, I go,
"This whole show, it’s just-- people
are going to be booing." You know?
-And everybody was, "No, no, it’s fine."
-Yeah.
Because I didn’t know how it worked.
-I didn’t know
that the audience is complicit
in the whole affair.
That’s funny.
So, you know, if they don’t laugh,
the warm-up guy
-stops the show...
-Yeah.
...berates them, and says
"Whenever the guy stops talking, laugh."
-You know?
-Right.
But how insulting is it
when you’re watching TV
and every joke kills?
I’m comforted by the fact that
most of these shows tank.
Here’s a company, okay,
and a television network.
"We’re going to make
a piece of entertainment.
We’re going to bring it to your
living room, give it to you for free."
And the public says, "We don’t want it."
How bad is that show?
If you don’t like a guy’s act,
any chance you’d like him?
Hmm.
-No.
-No?
When I grew up with cartoons,
there were good guys and bad guys.
But do you like this move
to conflicted characters?
[Jerry] What do you think?
-I don’t think you do.
-[Jerry] No.
-I think you like good versus bad.
-Yes.
This is my big beef with,
for example, James Bond.
You have a license to kill,
you have the fastest car in the world,
every girl wants to go to bed with you.
How about a smile?
-Yeah, right.
-How about a little smile once in a while?
-What’s all the internal strife?
-Yeah. Right, right.
Your last Letterman with
the World War I and II bit.
The only country that really worries me
is the country of Germany.
I don’t know if you guys are
history buffs or not, but...
[audience laughing]
[clapping]
In the early part
of the previous century,
Germany decided to go to war.
And who did they go to war with?
The world.
[audience laughing]
And so you figure that would take
about five seconds for the world to win.
But, no, it was actually close.
[audience laughing]
Then about 30 years pass,
and Germany decides, again,
to go to war, and again,
it chooses as its enemy, the world.
[audience laughing]
And this time they have that guy...
[mimicking Hitler]
-That guy.
-[audience laughing]
I have never heard more comics
talk about a bit.
And I heard
that you put a lot of work into that.
God damn right I did.
But you’d think at that point
the world would go,
"Listen, Germany, here’s the deal.
You don’t get to be a country no more
on account of you keep
attacking the world."
[audience laughing]
[Jerry] Think firemen should have
the day off when it’s raining?
[laughing]
[Jerry] Give them the day off.
Holy crow.
You say more things
that nobody says anymore.
I...
"Holy crow."
I haven’t heard that since ’58.
[groaning]
Jesus.
My son, when I went to see him in college,
you don’t know if your child’s gay,
you know what I mean?
-Right.
-Until he tells you.
So I’m always like,
super pro-gay just in case.
-Right.
-So I’m like...
I’m like, "My friend just came out.
We’re so happy, you know.
It’s good that he came out. He’s gay."
And then I began to think,
maybe my son thinks I’m gay now.
What if we each think each other is gay?
Leading secretive heterosexual lives.
Acting gay around each other
to make the other one not feel bad.
Right.
Larry Miller has the greatest joke
I’ve ever heard about Canada.
He says, "You go to Canada,
it’s like as if aliens had captured you,
brought you back to their planet,
and rebuilt what they thought was Earth,
but they can only see it
through telescopes.
And you would get out,
they would release you,
and you would walk into this,
what seemed like America,
and you’d go, 'Oh, great, I’m home.'
And then, you would slowly realize
that something is terribly wrong.
You’d go, 'Blue Dot Gasoline?
The Ford Commander?
What are these things?
This is not my home. I’m not home.'"
I’m impressed that you appreciate
the humor of that, as a Canadian.
You really have a lot to accomplish
in your remaining years?
My entire adult life is just
making comedy stuff.
And for some reason, it’s important to me
to make as much of it as I can.
Yeah.
-I imagine...
-Do you...
...a woodchuck has a similar mindset.
-A woodchuck?
-Yeah.
A woodchuck thinks, "I’m a woodchuck.
I’ve got to chuck wood...
as much as I can 'cause that’s my thing."
My son writes eight hours a day.
And he loves poetry.
-Really?
-Which... I don’t understand poetry.
-I don’t understand a single word.
-Poetry is bad standup.
[Jerry] It’s carefully chosen words
that have no laugh at the end.
[laughing]
[Jerry] Another cool thing about this car.
It has 99,900-something miles on it,
and today,
we will shoot this car
turning over the odometer.
It’s about to go over
100,000 miles. Look at this.
[engine revving]
Six. Seven.
Eight. Nine.
[Jerry groans] I can't do it.
I just can’t do it.